# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hi y’all, it’s Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享
In this episode, I’ll share
# 脆皮花生米
A snack called crispy peanuts
# 首先我们准备花生米500克放入盆中
First we prepare about 500 grams of peanuts into a bowl
# 然后加入适量的清水将其浸泡10分钟备用
Add some water to soak them for 10 minutes
# 这一步的目的是去除杂质和发涨花生皮
This is to rinse the peanuts and soften their skins
# 10分钟之后将花生米捞出沥干水分备用
After 10 minutes, get them out and dry
# 下一步开始调味上糊
Next it’s the seasoning and coating
# 首先在盆中加入鸡蛋2个
First, two eggs in the bowl
# 加入食用盐2勺（约3克）
Add about 2 spoons of salt
# 加入花椒面1克
One spoon of peppercorn powder
# 加入适量的辣椒面
Also some red chili powder
# 不能吃麻辣的同学可以不加
If you don’t handle hot food well, hold the peppercorn and chili powder
# 加入五香粉1勺（约2克）
Then a spoon and five-spices powder
# 然后搅拌均匀
Mix them well
# 搅拌均匀之后开始分多次加入面粉
After it’s well mixed, add flour in successively
# 同学们切记必须分多次加入
It’s really important that we add the flour in steps
# 直到花生米每一粒都颗粒分明即可
Until every peanut gets evenly coated
# 这一步的目的是给花生米穿上一层脆皮衣
This process is to make a crispy coat for the peanuts
# 如果不喜欢太多脆皮可以减少鸡蛋和面粉
If you like the coats lighter, hold the eggs and flour
# 最后再将多余的小面团筛除即可
At last, pick the redundant flour out
# 下一步开始制作
Now let’s cook the peanuts
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入宽油
Then add Kuan You (broad oil) in the wok
# 油温烧至5成热之后开始转小火
When the oil is about 150 degrees Celsius (300 degrees F), turn down the burner
# 再下入处理好的花生米
Drop the peanuts in
# 然后开中小火炸4分钟
Fry at mid-low temperature for 4 minutes
# 中途的时候用细漏去除脱落的细渣
Filter out the dropping scums during frying
# 这一步的目的是保护宽油的二次使用
So that we can still use the oil later
# 同学们炸制的时候必须随时推动花生米使其均匀受热
It’s important that we stir the peanuts during frying to make them evenly cooked
# 当花生米炸至略香之后即可捞出
When the aroma comes out, we can get the peanuts out of the wok
# 因为花生米的内部有强烈的预热会继续自熟
The high temperature inside the peanuts will continue cooking themselves
# 如果在锅中刚好够脆则说明已经炸制过火
If it’s already crispy out of the wok, it’s overcooked
# 炸制过火的花生米出锅冷却之后容易变糊
Then it will become dark and bitter as it cools down
# 4分钟之后捞出凉透即可食用
After 4 minutes, peanuts out of the wok and they will be ready once they cool down
# 一道香脆可口的脆皮花生米就制作完成
And our crispy peanuts are done!
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，不能吃辣的同学可以不加辣椒面和花椒
# 第二，最后上粉必须达到每一颗花生米颗粒分明
# 第三，新手在炸的过程中可以不断的捞出花生米尝口感，但必须小心花生米烫嘴
# 脆皮花生米的技术总结完毕
Now it’s the technical conclusion
First, if you don’t like the peanuts to be too hot, hold the red chili and peppercorn powder
Second, Make sure the peanuts are evenly coated
Third, as noobs, you can constantly taste the peanuts during frying to see the texture changing but be careful when they are hot!
That’s it for the conclusion of our “Crispy Peanuts”!